Guide to the James A. Perkins papers, 1941-1997.
Perkins, James A. papers, 1941-1997
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
James A. Perkins papers, 1941-1997.
3-10-3158
James Alfred Perkins 1911-
8.5 cubic ft.
Speeches, news clippings, subject files, photographs, corresponence, certificates.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers relating to James Perkins' career before coming to Cornell; speeches and articles; files relating to his inauguration as Cornell's president; files relating to activities at Cornell, including the events of 1969; subject files relating to other activities; a few photographs and personal letters; and certificates and honorary degrees.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
President, Cornell University, 1963-1969.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers relating to James Perkins' career before coming to Cornell; speeches and articles; files relating to his inauguration as Cornell's president; files relating to activities at Cornell, including the events of 1969; subject files relating to other activities; a few photographs and personal letters; and certificates and honorary degrees.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Perkins, James Alfred,1911-; Cornell University.Office of the President.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also James A. Perkins Papers, #3-10-1022.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Speeches, lectures, and addresses
Boxes 1 and 2
Series II. Articles
Boxes 3 and 4
Series III. Cornell Presidency
Boxes 4 and 5
Series IV. International Council for Educational Development
Boxes 5 and 6
Series V. Miscellaneous personal papers
(Letters, invitations, interviews, honorary degrees, clippings)
Boxes 6 and 7
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Speeches, lectures, and addresses
  - Public Administration Review- "Administration of the National Security Program", 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Report on Cooper Union for Advancement of Science and Art", June 12, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Training in Administration- University of the West Indies, April 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mount Allison Summer Institute, August 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Russian Research Center, Harvard- 10th Anniversary "A Wider Public for Area Studies", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Southern Regional Education Board-"National Security and Higher Education", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Association of Princeton Graduate Alumni, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Campus-Forgotten Field.. ."- Admin. in the Halls of Ivy Symposium Public Admin. Review, Winter 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Power of the Democratic Idea" - The Rockefeller Panel Report, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Moral Judgments in Academic Structures" Conference on.. .Democratic Way of Life, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Commencement Address- Loomis School, June 9, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yale 1935 Class Dinner, March 11, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Private Foundation & Public Interest"- National Council on Community Foundations, Inc., May 12, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Case Inst. of Technology Commencement- "The New Community", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University of Akron- "Importance of Graduate Work", Dec. 13, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ohio University-"The Growing World of the University", May 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report of President's Advisory Panel on National Academy of Foreign Affairs, December 17, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Council for Independent School Aid Speech, April 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Deans in my Life- Tower Club, May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Inauguration Address-"The Future of Cornell", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - John F. Kennedy Memorial Convocation- Cornell University, November 23, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Education and Freedom of Mind"- Atlantic City-Middle States Conference, December 5, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NYU 6th Biennial Conference on Charitable Foundations, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "What the New Foundation Executive Should Know", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Commencement Address- Cornell University, June 15, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Exploding Knowledge and Academic Community"- Brown University Bicentennial, September 28, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - ACE Annual Convention- "The New Conditions of Autonomy"- San Francisco, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "The New Venture" and "The Heart of the Matter"- Cornell University, September 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Should You Go to College?"- Philadelphia Bulletin Magazine interview, January 24, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - University of Vienna, 600th Anniversary, April 15, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cornell University Centennial Celebration- NYC, Lincoln Center, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Call on Pres. Perkins at Cornell"- Princeton Quarterly, Spring 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - University of Rochester- "Attention Must Be Paid", June 6, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "The Spirit of the University" - Commencement Address for Cornell University, June 14, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Living with Science" - Experimental Science, November 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The University of the Arts, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Should the Artist Come to Campus?"- Saturday Review, July 17, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Universities and the Arts (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Gold Medal Acceptance Speech- National Institute of Social Sciences, December 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "The State of the University" - Speech to Board of Trustees, October 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Long Island University 40th Anniversary- "The New Missions of the Private University" NYC, February 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "The Responsibility of Power" - NY Times editorial, February 1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Three Missions of a University"- Princeton Alumni Weekly, March 15, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Role of the Univ. in State's Future"- Agricultural Leader's Forum, March 24, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Challenge & Response in Foreign Aid"- NY Times editorial, March 28, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "The Scholar-Modern Style"- Hamilton College Commencement, June 5, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "The Etiquette of University Debate"- Cornell Commencement, June 13, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "The University or the Transistor"- NY Times article, June 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Foreign Aid and the Brain Drain"- Foreign Affairs, July 1966 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Strategie Planificatrice"- Symposium de Delos, July 1966 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Education and the State"- Board of Regents NY state 92nd Convocation held in Albany, NY, September 21, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Japan International Christian University Foundation (Women's Planning Committee)- New York City, October 21, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "The Price of Choice"- College Entrance Examination Board, October 25, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Business and Education", November 16, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Chief School Officers"- Report of NY State Regents Advisory Committee on Educational Leadership, December 1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Reviews of James Perkins', The University in Transition, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "Liberal Learning and the Learning Community"- Association of American Colleges Meeting, January 17, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "On Ideals and Experience"- University of Illinois Honors Day Convocation, May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "College and University Presidents"- NY State Regents Advisory1 Committee on Educational Leadership, May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Commencement Address- Cornell University, June 12, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - "The Disquiet Americans & Local Wars"- NY Times editorial, July 1, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Convocation Address- Hampton Institute, September 28, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Addresses & Summary Report- International Conference on World Crisis in Education held in Williamsburg, VA, October 5-9, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools- Boston, Mass., December 8, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - "The Restless Decade"- Cornell University Convocation held in NYC, March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - "The Restless Student"- Bilderberg Conference & YWCA luncheon, April 27 & October 16, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance Programs, October 1968 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - "The Restless Student"- Reprint from Minerva, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "Cornell's Second Century", May 9, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - "The University's Role in Higher Education Systems"- 10th Congress of Commonwealth Universities held in Australia, August 1968 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - "The University and the New Priorities-National Industrial Conference Board held in New York City, November 1968 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - "The New Environment"- Notre Dame University, June 2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "The Moral Imperative", January 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Black in the White University"- United Negro College Fund- Washington D.C., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Integrity of the University"- Cornell Daily Sun, February 5, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Draft of UCLA speech (not delivered), April 16, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tower Club Paper- Annual Meeting of Tower Club of Cornell University, May 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Future of the Professional Schools"- American Society for Engineering Education- Forth Distinguished Lecture held at Penn State, June 25, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Overloading the Private Sector"- NY Times editorial, October 4, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The University and Society"-UNESCO Symposium, February 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "University as Part of Larger Society"-draft (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Can University Governance be More Democratic?"- University of Hawaii; later reprinted in Higher Education For All, January 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut Council for Higher Education, October 24, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - University of Wisconsin, January 24, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Graduate Education, International Studies and National Interest"- University of Florida, February 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Buffalo Council on World Affairs, April 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "The University-Old Ghosts and New"-DAEDALUS, Fall 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Look, Ma, No Hands"- NY Times editorial, January 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ICED: German-U.S. Study Group on Access to Higher Ed. in U.S. & Germany, April 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "The International Dimension of Higher Education"-ACE Annual Meeting, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Autonomy" for the International Encyclopedia, December 1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Four Axims.. .in Higher Education"- European Center for Higher Education; Bucharest, September 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Katharine McBride Memorial Service- Bryn Mawr College, October 1, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "American College Through Foreign Eyes"- Spelman College, October 16, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie For Advancement of Teaching, November 15, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Design and Management of Systems of Higher Education-Paris, November 18, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Problems of Access to Higher Ed."- Report of 2nd IAU Round Table, April 6, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The International Movement of Students and Staff- held in Vancouver, August 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Potency of Racism"- Atlantic Monthly editorial, January 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "F. Emerson Andrews"- Foundation Center Annual Report, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "The Global Context/The U.S. Role" CHEAR Conference, February 26, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "International Scope of American Higher Education"- SUNY Buffalo, April 16, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Foreign Policy Association, May 3, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Foreign Policy, Global Ed., and National Interest"- State Dept. Talk, June 13, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Future of Higher Ed. in an Interdependent World" - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, June 18, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - International Education in a Troubled World- Jefferson, VT, August 1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - National Academy of Education, October 19, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "The Foreign Grad. Student, the University and Government Policy"- Orlando, Florida, December 6, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Designing Research Projects in the Field of Education, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Designing Research Projects in the Field of Education- Ajijic, Mexico, February 4, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Designing Research Programs on the Subject of Access to Higher Education- Ajijic, Mexico, February 11, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - UN Foreign Language Week Celebration, March 19, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Access to Higher Education" International Association of Universities- Manila, August 26, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "Universal Trends in Higher Education..."- Brasilia, December 1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "The International Dr. Perkins"- Exxon Education Foundation Report, January 1981 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Foreign Language and International Study"- National Forum, Spring 1981 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Marymount College Speech, March 26, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "U.S. Foreign Education Through Foreign Eyes"- Swarthmore College, April 2-4, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "International Dimensions in Higher Ed." - Western College Association in Honolulu, April 9, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "National Interest in Foreign Language and International Studies"- University of New Hampshire, April 16, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Educational System of Tomorrow" for Gallup Book, August 3, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "Social Studies in Elementary Schools"- Social Education, October 1981 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - James Perkins' Review of Paul Simon's, The Tongue-Tied American in Change, October 1981 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - James Perkins' book review of H. B. Wells' book Being There in The Journal of Higher Education, December 1981 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Santo Domingo-CAMESA, February 5, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Puerto Rico- GULERPE, February 10, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Askwith Lecture at Harvard, April 6, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "Research and Policy- Making in Higher Education"- Stockholm, June 1982 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Future of Swarthmore College"- Swarthmore College, June 1982 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "The Governance of Higher Education"- Report for Education Department of World Bank, November 1983 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - "Communication and Cooperation for the Development of Education"- AISEI, February 25, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - James Perkins' Review of B. R. Clark's The Higher Education System in The Journal of Higher Education, March/April 1985 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - European Institute of Education and Social Policy- Paris, January 23, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - "From Carnegie to Cornell" (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Chief State School Officers (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Articles, various talks, 1948-1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "Ideas" for articles and speeches, 1959-1966 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Collected Speeches, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Collected Speeches, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Collected Speeches, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Unidentified or missing speeches/articles etc. (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Series II. Articles
  - "The Economic Future of Europe"- National Petroleum Association in Atlantic City, September 17, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Advice to the Eager Neophyte"- reprinted from Public Administration Review, Summer 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Military Services and Their Role in the Making of National Policy, November 19, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Our Expanding Worlds"- Commencement Address for Centre College in Danville, Kentucky, June 8, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Council of Community Foundations (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "The University Community"- University of Toronto, November 26, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The Integrity of the University Community"- Varsity Graduate; University of Toronto, Spring 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Education- -The Year 2000"- National Association of Manufacturers, December 7, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "The University and the Arts"- Chi Psi Fraternity Bulletin, Summer 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Cornell Planning Conference on International Education- Williamsburg, Virginia, February 15-18, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - First Plenary Session: Addresses (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - University of Notre Dame Commencement Speech, June 2, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "The University and Due Process", 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "The University as Community"- Commencement speech at SUNY Binghamton, June 15, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - University Administration: The Changing Concept of University Autonomy (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "The University and the New Priorities"- Cornell University Report of the President, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cornell University Commencement Address, June 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Vanderbilt University, February 5, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - "The Future of the Professional Schools", 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Commentary on Sanders & Ward's book, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - "The Educational Revolution", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - "The Crisis of the University", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - "The University and Society"- Bilderberg Conference, April 1970 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "The Five Crises of the University- The UNESCO Courier, June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Higher Education in the 1970's", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "To Participate or Not to Participate", June 1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Commentary on "Higher Education in Nine Countries" by Barbara Burn, Jan. 26, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "The Arts on Campus: Necessity for Change" (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Occasional Paper #1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Occasional Paper #2, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "The Drive for Coordination"- Voice of America Forum, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "The Future of Coordination"- Voice of America Forum, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Organization and Functions of the University", 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "Coordinating Federal State or Institutional Decisions", 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - French articles, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Book Review of Being Lucky by Herman B. Wells for The Journal of Higher Education, January 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - "International Education in a Troubled World"- coauthored with Barbara B. Burn, February 1980 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Article for Social Education, April 1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gallup Poll, August 8, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Princeton University, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Office of Price Administration, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Photographs (Stanford University & Ozone Club), March 22, 1946 & December 2, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Century Association, 1950-1963 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - National Academy for Foreign Affairs, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - New York State Board of Regents Professorships in Humanities & Science, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Air Force Systems Command, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - National Fund For Medical Education, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - National Scholarship Service and Fund For Negro Students, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Presidential Advisors on Major International Problems, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Ithaca Regional Planning Board, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Ithaca Regional Planning Board- publications, 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - President's Assistance Programs- President's Advisory Committee, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Student Freedom Movement & Campus Revolution (not Cornell)- articles and speeches, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Student Freedom Movement & Campus Revolution (not Cornell)- articles and speeches, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Student Freedom Movement & Campus Revolution (not Cornell)- articles and speeches, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - President's General Advisory Committee on Foreign Assistance, 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Ideas of Democracy in Transitional Societies- Italy Conference, April 1966 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - National Association of Manufacturer's Congress of American Industry, December 1966 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Williamsburg Conference held in Virginia, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Johnson Foundation/ Prairie School, March 15, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Near East Emergency Donations, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Near East Emergency Donations (continued), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - UNESCO- Paris Meeting, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Center on the University-proposal, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - NET/Channel 13 Merger Study, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - University of Hawaii, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Senate Hearing on Emergency School Aid, March 18, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - South Asian Relief Assistance Advisory Panel, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - German Marshall Fund (Howard University), June 5, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Trilateral Commission & Northeast Consortium for Andean Studies, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Education- Paris, 1972-85 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Aid and Development Countries, 1974? (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - International Council for Educational Development, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mark Twain Society, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Presidential Committee on Foreign Language and International Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - IASEI- Mexico, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Presidental Committee on Foreign Language and International Studies & American Council on Education, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - National Council on Foreign Language and International Studies, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General Advisory Committee on Arms Control and Disarmament, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Background Papers for Committee, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Arms Control and Disarmament Background Papers for Committee, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Higher Education in the United States, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - James Perkins' Appointment to Presidency (Cornell), January 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Series III. Cornell Presidency
  - Cornell contract, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - James Perkins' Inauguration, October 4, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (A), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (B), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (C), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (D-O), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (P-R), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous Correspondence (S-Z), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cornell University (miscellaneous materials), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Random newspaper clippings (Cornell University), 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Biology (Cornell University), 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - NY Regents Commission on Educational Leadership, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Cornell Centennial Campaign- Waldorf-Astoria, January 24, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Cornell Commencement Celebrations, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Report of the President (Cornell University), 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Report of the President (Cornell University), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Report of the President (Cornell University), 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Law School, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Commencement, June 14, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Cornell Latin American Year, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Professors-at-Large (Cornell University), April 30, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)